Md. Mohaiminul Hasan

mohaiminul.hasan.ewu@gmail.com • +88 017 01 00 91 98 github.com/mdmuai13 • linkedin.com/in/md-mohaiminul-hasan • mohaiminul.info

Summary

Senior software engineer with a bachelor's in computer science and 4+ years of experience in software development industries. As an experienced and results-driven Software Engineer, I bring a comprehensive skill set to the table that is tailor-made for any organization seeking to enhance its technological capabilities and worked with stakeholders to create enterprise products. I have successfully led numerous teams in delivering game-changing software solutions that have redefined the way we interact with the digital world.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Algosolver LLC

Jackson Ave, Long Island City, NY, USA (Remote)

March 2021-Present

- Responsible for designing and implementing system architecture and led the development team for multiple client projects.
- Developed the in-house product *woofmeets.com* from an idea to a fully-functional platform, resulting in a good number of user engagements within the first two months of launch.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to create a sustainable business model and designed a system architecture that aligned with the company's vision.
- Continuously monitored user feedback and made necessary improvements to enhance the user experience and increase customer satisfaction.

Backend Engineer, Landknock Ltd

Baridhara, Dhaka, Bangladesh

July 2020-January 2021

- Developed and maintained RESTful API for SaaS applications, resulting in an increase in user satisfaction by 30%.
- Optimized SQL queries to reduce the response time by up to 70% of some specific APIs.
- Participated in the design and architecture of software systems to improve performance and scalability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software products within tight deadlines

Full Stack Developer

Radyan It Inc, Dallas, Texas (Remote)

September 2018–February 2019

• Developed an E-commerce application for the furniture domain.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science

East West University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

May 2015-December 2019

Thesis: Paraphrase question answering using Recurrent Neural Network in the Bengali language.

Skills

Language: Typescript, Javascript, PHP, Go, Java, C, C++, Dart, Solidity

Backend: Node.js, Express Js, Nest Js, PHP, Laravel, Go

Frontend: React Js, Next Js, PHP, Flutter, Svelte

Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, SQLite, Firebase

Tools: Socket.io, Docker, Swagger, AWS, ElasticSearch, Firebase, Supabase, FCM, Cloudflare